-你好  卡侬妮卡  -克莱尔  你在干什么
- Good day, Calonice. - Claire, what are you doing?
想事情
Thinking.
你现在应该上台了
You're supposed to be on-stage right now.
卡侬妮卡  我受不了了
"Calonice, it's more than I can bear.
满脑子想着性事  燥热得不行
I am hot all over with blushes for our sex.
男人们说我们是狡猾的流氓
Men say we're slippery rogues..."
他们说得不对吗
"And aren't they right?"
走吧  我们走
Come on, let's go.
走啊
Come on.
我们早晚都会死
We're all gonna die one day.
什么
What?
我会死
I'm gonna be dead,
你会死
you're gonna be dead.
他们都会死
They're all gonna be dead.
所有人
Everybody.
你究竟在说什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
那是我的耳环吗
Are those my earrings?
我以为你不会介意
I... didn't think you'd care.
你去吧
You do it.
《利西翠妲》是古希腊早期喜剧作家
阿里斯多芬尼斯的作品
讲述利西翠妲鼓动交战城邦的女性"性罢工"
以结束战争
你来演利西翠妲  台词你都知道  对吧
You be Lysistrata. You know all my lines, right?
你不能就
You can't just--
演出怎么办  克莱尔
What about the show? Claire!
翻译   煮粥达人
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   肉松
翻译   WalkingNerd
翻译   盐湖凉开水
时间轴   大葱
后期   饿得慌
校对  草草
顾问  老杜
总监  草草
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
纸牌屋
第六季  第五集
我们就快好了  得再调一下灯光
We are almost good. We just have to adjust the lights.
没关系
That's fine.
我非常感谢您来参加访谈
I did want to thank you personally for doing this.
我真的很感激
I really appreciate it.
等我们完事后再谢吧
Wait till we're finished before you do that.
我不会问不该问的问题
Well, I won't deviate from the questions.
你什么都可以问  只要是与
You can ask me anything, as long as it's about the...
总统有关的
the president.
-能别给我弄那个吗  -抱歉
- Can you get away from me with that? - My apologies.
-这样就行了  -抱歉  谢泼德先生
- I'm fine. - Sorry, Mr. Shepherd.
化妆是因为光非常亮
It's just that the lights are pretty harsh.
没事  开始吧
It's fine. Let's go.
俄罗斯霸权条款
This Russia debacle,
基本上就是向
it's essentially a 20% tax
去该地区帮忙的美国公司
on American companies that are just over there
收取20%的税
trying to help out the region.
这是本届政府近来
It's the latest in a series of...
频频做出的灾难决策的最新一条
disastrous steps taken by this White House.
就难怪
And you wonder--
难怪国会要立法
You wonder why Congress was looking at legislation
拿走她的核武公文包
to take the nuclear button away from her.
作为一名爱国者
As a patriot,
作为一名热爱祖国和自己公司的美国人
as an American who loves his country and, yes, his company,
我们可以做得更好
we can do better.
我们可以做得远比现在好
We can do so much better.
总统在哪里
就连比尔·谢泼德
Even Bill Shepherd,
他以前从不接受采访
who the last time he was interviewed on air was never--
马修·道得
ABC新闻政治分析家
就连他都感到非发声不可了
Even he felt compelled to speak out.
马修·道得
ABC新闻政治分析家
她是我党首脑  我得说我感到困惑
She's the head of my party, and I have to say, I'm at a loss.
斯蒂芬妮·库特
民主党参谋
她的整个日程都是空的
Her entire schedule is empty.
以前也有总统失踪
Presidents have gone missing before--
但是在戴维营清理思绪
But there's a difference between clearing your head at Camp David
有严重强迫症的天才大亨
可参见电影《飞行家》
和跟霍华德·休斯一样闭门不出不是一回事
and going full-blown Howard Hughes.
她已经三周没有公开露面  也没有任何消息
She hasn't been seen publicly in three weeks or heard from.
除了某日半夜赦免了她丈夫的幕僚长
Except for a late night pardon for her husband's chief of staff.
而很多人认为这是个战略错误
Which many consider a strategic mistake.
道格·斯坦普是有问题的
Well, Doug Stamper has issues.
她政府的每个人都有问题
Everyone in her administration has issues.
新闻发言人肖恩·杰弗瑞斯辞职了
Sean Jeffries, the press secretary, has resigned.
可能还会有更多人离任
And there are probably more departures to come.
她的内阁已经受够了
Her cabinet has had enough.
如果她认为一次赦免就能摆脱联邦检察官
And if she thinks a pardon is gonna keep the US Attorney away,
-她可就...  -她
- she's-- - She's--
-抑郁了  -我说不好是不是抑郁
- Depressed. - I don't know about depressed.
悲伤统帅
她看上去不是精神失常就是很抑郁
You know, she looks either very disturbed, or depressed.
但是  精神失常  能那样说吗
But, I mean, "disturbed"? Can you really say that?
是的  等等
Yeah. Look, hold on.
我对她的领导能力有很大的疑问
I'm asking a very real question about her ability to lead here.
你们见过这张照片吗  我们见过
Have you seen this photo? Because we have.
我们不想妄下诊断
Now we're not here to diagnose,
但你看到这张照片  肯定会心生怀疑
but you look at this, and you need to ask.
从国家的角度来讲
On behalf of our country,
那个女人让我们的外交政策倒退了30年
that woman undid 30 years of foreign policy
她表现得像个  原谅我说脏话  像个[怂包]
by acting like, pardon my French, a...
总统在逃避什么
但是现在  我们进入了一个新阶段
But now, now we're into a new phase.
白宫灯火辉煌  却无人坐镇
When the White House lights are on, but nobody's home.
她倒是在里面  但不肯出来
I mean, she's home, but she won't leave.
已经缩在那里23天了  还没有要出来的意思
Been hunkered down in there for 23 days and counting.
显然  她已经停止工作了
Apparently, she's stopped doing anything.
她瘫痪了
She's paralyzed.
一个瘫痪的[臭娘们]
A paralyzed...
而最危险的就是一个瘫痪的[臭娘们]
And there's nothing more dangerous than a paralyzed...
说真的  我觉得她可能是有史以来
Seriously, I think she might be the worst thing
这个国家最糟糕的灾难
that has ever happened to this country.
紧急求救
SOS.
救救我们的灵魂  救救我们的大船
Save our souls, save our ships,
这两个说法都合适
Take your pick.
这可不是闹着玩的
This ... is real.
我是梅乐蒂·科鲁兹  这就是我的评论
I'm Melody Cruz, and that's what I got.
那张抓拍真不错  是不是
That's quite a snapshot, right?
独一无二  精心设计过
Unique. Carefully calibrated.
痛苦  歇斯底里再加一点点疯狂
Pain, hysteria and just a small dose of crazy.
他们从未见过这样的克莱尔·安德伍德
Claire Underwood, like they've never seen before.
其实没有看上去那么简单
It's actually not as easy as it looks.
要摆出那样的表情
See, in order for me to make that face,
我得发挥想象
I have to imagine...
把各种情绪完美糅合到一起
the perfect combination of things.
配方如下
Here's the recipe.
首先  我得想着
First, I have to think about all the ways
我这一生中  男人操控我的各种办法
in which men have tried to manage me my whole life.
然后  我要想到
Then, I think of...
美国民众最担心的事
America's worst fear...
就一个女人坐进总统办公室而言
when it comes to a female in the Oval Office.
-她的日程全推干净了  -最后
- Her schedule has been cleared. - And finally...
我最后悔的事  弗兰西斯·J·安德伍德
...my biggest regret-- Francis J. Underwood.
总统女士
Madam President.
你病了吗
Are you ill?
要是病了  我去请白宫医生
If you're ill, I'll call the White House physician.
克莱尔
Claire.
出去  马克
Just get out, Mark.
克莱尔  不能再这样下去了
Claire, this has to stop.
请让我一个人静静
Please, just leave me alone.
你引发了全国性的恐慌  你得振作起来
You are alarming the nation. You need to get up.
听着
Listen.
我准备了一段简短的声明
I've prepared a short statement
解释你之前为何不露面  并宣布回归
explaining your absence and announcing your return.
你可以今天下午在玫瑰园发表声明
You can deliver it in the Rose Garden this afternoon.
这是为了我们好
I promise you this is for both of our sakes.
你不明白
You don't understand...
请先回避
If you would, please.
克莱尔
Claire...
看着我
look at me.
-看着我  -出去
- Look at me. - Get out.
出去吧
Please get out.
-别管我  -你这样不仅是自掘坟墓
- Just leave me alone. - You are not only digging your own grave,
还在葬送你的总统职位  别再这样了
you are burying the presidency. Stop it.
你努努力
You can try.
-努努力好吗  -不行  马克
- Can you try? - I can't, Mark.
我做不到
I just can't.
I can't.
别担心
Don't worry.
我有计划
I have a plan.
抱歉
Excuse me.
先生
Sir.
没问题吧
We're good here?
好  谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
是多疑还是应当
Was it paranoia or is it due diligence?
你说呢  马克
You tell me, Mark.
我们刚刚见识了这个贱人多有能耐
We both just lived through what that bitch is capable of.
肯定是出了什么问题
Something is definitely wrong.
她...
She...
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
她连说话都缺乏条理
I mean, she can't even put two sentences together.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我从来没见过她这样  她一团乱
I've never seen her like this. She's a mess.
那么
Well...
不管怎样  这改变不了我们的处境
Either way, that doesn't change where we are.
还有  马克
And, Mark...
康威垮掉后
when Conway imploded,
我们发现你有些
we recognized that you were a little squea--
太过谨慎  没有立即上位
squeamish about stepping in.
我们很欣赏这一点
And we appreciate that.
但现在是时候了
But it's time.
你会成为一个伟大的总统的
You'll make a great president.
我们会确保的
We'll see to that.
等等  我们把话说明白
Now, wait, wait. Let's be clear, okay?
我知道我们一直在狠狠打压她
I know we've been hitting her pretty hard,
但我不能允许再对她下一次手
but I can't condone another attempt.
-我做不到  -冷静
- I can't. - Calm down.
天啊  马克  说真的
My God, Mark. I mean, really.
还有其他办法
There are other ways.
好  我们是要弹劾她
Okay, so we're talking about impeachment
还是国会政府
or a congressional government?
第25修正案第四款
25th Amendment, Section 4.
从来没人用过
Which has never been used.
是为了迅速扼杀信心危机
It's built for speed, intended to smother a crisis of confidence.
让民众安心
Reassure the public.
让世界安心
Reassure the world
美国政府还能继续运作
that continuity remains at the American government,
就算总统变得...
even if a president becomes...
-无法履行他的职责  -她的职责
- Unable to fulfill his duties. - Her duties.
-前提是她无法胜任  -她现在确实无法胜任
- It requires her to be unfit. - And she is.
而且
I mean...
我们的律师已经查过了
our lawyers have already looked into this.
她只要能力不足就行
She only needs to be deficient.
法律写得模棱两可  可以变通
The language is vague and accommodating.
马克  如果你对此
Mark, if you have any doubt about this
-有所顾虑  -继续说
- at all-- - I'm just listening.
内阁听命于你
The Cabinet is yours.
你在参众两院都有关系
You have relationships inside the Senate, the House,
两党也都有人脉
on both sides of the aisle.
非常合适
It's a natural fit.
但这事必须做得
But the thing has to cascade with--
天衣无缝
Precision.
先由副总统和内阁多数成员
A chain reaction beginning with a letter to Congress,
联名写信给国会
signed by the vice president
建议弹劾我
and a majority of his Cabinet,
然后形成连锁反应
recommending my removal from office.
我怎么会猜到他们的招数
And how do I know that's what they'll try to do?
因为第25条就是冲我来的
Because the 25th gets personal.
比尔喜欢我做落难少女
Bill likes me being the damsel in distress.
想得美吧
He wishes I were.
你去哪儿
Where you headed?
我在北方有家人
I have family up north.
哪儿
Where?
北方
North.
凯茜的姐姐还在科德角吗
Cathy's sister still on the Cape?
在海恩尼斯  是吧
Hyannis, right?
很好
It's good.
家人很重要
Family's important.
尤其是在艰难时刻
Especially during trying times--
我也想请你进来  但我真的...
I'd invite you in, but I really--
有些事我总想不通
There's still something that I can't get straight.
你再跟我说一遍吧  当时
If we could go through it one more time. So...
她被一辆车接去医生那儿
She was picked up by car to be taken to the doctor.
她不太舒服
She wasn't feeling well.
直到她发生栓塞前你一直跟她在一起
You were with her the whole time leading up to the embolism?
斯坦普先生  够了
Mr. Stamper, enough!
我只想弄清怎么回事
I'm just trying to understand what happened.
你别再来缠着我了
I don't need you coming around here anymore.
你清楚是怎么一回事
You know exactly what happened.
也知道验尸结果  事情就是这样
You have the coroner's conclusions. And that's that.
我还在哀悼我妻子
I'm in mourning for my wife,
我不想再提起她生命的最后时刻
and I'm not reliving the final moments of her life anymore.
不想跟你提
Not with you.
我觉得你妻子是被谋杀的
I think your wife was murdered.
我要关门了
I'm closing the door now.
-喂  -道格  我是弗莱德·安博格
- Hello. - Doug. Fred Amburg here.
-这是谁的电话  -我的
- Whose phone is this? - This one's mine.
我刚出来
I just got out.
我才知道
I had no idea.
我今早还跟科尔通过话
I talked to Cole this morning.
我听说了件我们那位心理医生的事
Heard an interesting thing about our esteemed shrink.
他休假了  事假
You know, that sabbatical, leave,
去旅行了  随你怎么说
walkabout, whatever you want to call it.
你在找他  是吧
You are looking for him, aren't you?
对
Yes.
他在弗吉尼亚州的一间小屋
He's in a cabin down in Virginia.
给
Here you go.
我可以...
Would you mind if I...?
谢谢
Thanks.
喂
Oh, hello?
别说话  别开口  等着
Don't say another word. Don't speak. Just wait.
抱歉  我拐错弯  跑进楼梯井了
My apologies, I took a wrong turn and wound up in some stairwell.
我们时间不多  得赶回楼上
We don't have much time until we have to get back upstairs.
玛茜最初跟我提这个想法时
When Marcy first came to me with this proposition,
豪不夸张地说  我震惊了
I was stunned, to say the least.
直到近来
Until recently I--
我才...我没想到事情会这么糟
I don't know. I didn't realize how truly bad things were.
但赶总统下台  我的天啊
But unseat the president? Jesus Christ.
总统是我的朋友
President's my friend.
虽说我担心她的精神状况
And while I worry about her mental state,
但我更担心国家的状况
I worry about the state of this nation more.
副总统先生  我很敬佩你
Mr. Vice President, I admire you greatly.
但我不习惯做这种事
But I'm not used to this kind of thing.
背地里谋算
Back rooms, after hours.
我们得一万个小心
We need to take every precaution.
光是过来就很危险了
And yet we're still at risk just by being here.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
但我相信总统一职的神圣性
but I believe in the sanctity of the office of the presidency.
所以我们才聚在这里
And that's exactly why we're here.
你这是让我们背弃誓言
You're asking us to betray an oath.
我是让大家吐露心声
I'm asking you to speak your mind.
这里的每个人齐心协力
A concentrated effort, all of us in this room.
我们或许救不了总统
We may not be able to save the president,
但或许救得了我们的政府
but we may just be able to save our administration.
第25条不仅要看准时机
The 25th is not just about timing.
还要绝对保密
It's about secrecy.
参议院一向守不住秘密
And the Senate hasn't kept a secret--
厄尔  感谢你提到这一点
Earl, I appreciate that.
众议院已在我掌控之中  参议院也交给我
I have the House, and I'll take care of the Senate.
我会起草一封信
I'll prepare a letter
详细列出总统的渎职
detailing the president's dereliction of duty,
向国会和后世解释清楚
laying out a case for Congress and for posterity.
等时机成熟  就会通知大家
And when the time comes, you'll all be notified.
我们都是爱国者
Look, we're all patriots here.
我们最牵挂的  我们唯一牵挂的  必须是
Our first concern, our only concern, has got to be...
国家的生死存亡
the survival of our nation.
该死
Fuck!
坐下吧  深呼吸
Sit and take a deep breath.
坐下
Sit down.
罗森医生  坐下
Dr. Rosen, sit down.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我想  你在这儿是因为你很痛苦
I'm assuming you're here because you're suffering.
如果不是为佐伊·巴恩斯
And if it's not over Zoe Barnes,
就是为另一个被你毁掉的人
it's over some other soul that you've torn apart.
不对
No.
你想  我在这儿
You're assuming I'm here
是因为我发现了你拿走了我什么东西
because I figured out what you took from me.
-拿走  -没给我
- Took? - Kept.
所有个人物品都应该在出院时归还原主
All personal property should have been returned upon release.
你说得对  是应该
You're right. It should have.
专业人士竟然做出这种事
There's no accounting for the behavior of supposed professionals.
我曾经在社交场合遇到过一个心理医生
I once met this psychologist, socially,
她跟我说
who told me about
她曾经给同僚们办了一次派对
a party that she hosted once for a group of her peers.
请了一屋子的心理医生
It was just a roomful of shrinks.
那晚派对结束后  她在打扫
At the end of the night, she was cleaning up,
走进卫生间
she went into the bathroom
发现她的某个同事把屎
and she saw that one of her colleagues had smeared shit
糊了一墙
all over the bathroom wall.
什么变态会做出那种事
Now, what kind of fucked up person would do something like that?
看来传言是真的
Well, I guess it's true what they say.
心理医生才是最变态的
That shrinks are the most fucked up of all.
那种行为很是暴力
Such a violence to that act.
但暴力很有趣
But violence is a funny thing.
其实受害者记得最清楚的
You know, it's not so much the physical pain
不是肉体上的疼痛
that can victims can remember.
而是当时的感觉
It's the feelings around it.
那种恐惧
The fear.
在哪  你扣下的遗嘱在哪  你放哪了
Where is it? The will you intercepted? Where is it?
已经不在我这儿了
I don't have it anymore.
不在我这儿
I don't have it!
里面写了什么
What was in it?
他把一切都留给了你
He left you everything.
天啊
God...
拿着吧
Take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我当时就觉得那么问很奇怪
I thought it was a strange question.
什么
What?
你问我弗兰西斯·安德伍德留给我什么了
When you asked me what Francis Underwood had given me.
遗嘱的结语就是这样的
That's how the will ends.
"记住我最后给你的那样东西"
"Remember the last thing I gave you."
别给她打电话  否则我会回来的
Don't call her or I'll be back.
希望你能搞清楚自己的问题  医生
Hope you figure out your problems, Doctor.
拿走吧
Take it.
想要的话  就送你了
If you want it, it's yours.
你想没想过  自己过的是别人的生活
Do you ever wonder if you're living somebody else's life?
你过的是谁的生活  简
Whose life are you living, Jane?
我在问你呢
Not me. You.
你好像饱受身份困扰
You seem to be struggling with your identity.
希望这样说现任总统不会太...
If that's not too impertinent to say to a...
冒昧
sitting president.
过来陪我换睡衣吧
Come keep me company while I put my jammies on.
帮我一下
Please.
你在葬礼上佯装顺从
Your little show of compliance at the funeral
却和维克多私下达成协议
as you made your side deal with Victor.
让我不禁想
Makes me wonder.
现在呢
And now what?
你现在演的是哪一出
What do you call this show?
怎样在短短三周内让三亿两千三百万人都反对你
How to turn 323 million people against you in three short weeks?
恭喜  克莱尔
Congratulations, Claire.
你现在让所有人头疼
You've become a problem for everybody.
还有
And...
你要知道
Just so you know,
叙利亚可能无可挽回了
Syria may be too far gone.
告诉我该怎么办  简
Tell me what to do, Jane.
我今晚参加了一个活动
I was at an event tonight.
通常  总统都会参加
An event the president usually attends.
今晚过得如何
And how was that evening?
正在形成的风暴很难对付
The storm that's gathering is a rough one.
你觉得他们什么时候会动手
When you think they'll strike?
我不知道
I have no idea.
有点晚了
It's late.
我正是这意思
That's exactly what I'm saying.
我想我该搬出去了
I think I should move out.
我理解
I understand.
你再这么下去  总统女士
Stick to this course, Madam President,
那么...
and...
座无虚席呢
Full house.
你们想必是想听不同的答案
You must be looking for different answers
这相同的问题已经问了...
to the same questions we've been going over for the last--
24天
Now, 24 days.
而总统仍然没离开官邸
And the president still hasn't left the residence.
-我只能说...  -凯尔茜  拜托
- And this is where I say-- - Kelsey, come on.
目前  与俄罗斯所达成的旨在维系
For now, the ground-breaking accord with Russia,
叙利亚公正且持久的和平的突破性协议
which aims for a just and lasting peace in Syria,
就足以说明一切
speaks for itself.
那么
So,
除非各位还有其他问题
unless there are any more questions,
应该说新的问题  请说
or shall I say new questions? Yes.
真正操盘的人是不是副总统
Isn't the vice president really the one running the show,
实质上掌控了总统实权
essentially acting as president?
有些内阁成员也这么说
There are members of the cabinet who are saying as much.
首先  提及白宫事宜时
Well, firstly, I would refrain from using the word "show,"
不建议使用"操盘"这种字眼
when it comes to the White House.
那么  今天就到此结束
And-- yeah. That's all for today.
谢谢
Thank you.
你确定不饿吗
Are you sure you're not hungry?
汤还不错
The soup is quite nice.
我不知道你怎么能...
I don't know how you can--
吃得下吗
Eat?
不  我...
No, I'm...
很高兴见你恢复食欲
glad to see you're eating.
总统女士  情势已经无法挽救
Madam President, it's beyond repair.
到了这个地步  你明白吧
You understand that, at this point?
你失去了国会的支持
You've lost the Hill.
失去了内阁的支持
You've lost your cabinet.
失去了国家的支持
You've lost the country.
你输了
You've lost.
你所属的政党也找不到理由支持你
Your own party can't even find a reason to support you.
我恳求你
I entreat you--
恳求我
You entreat me?
辞职
Resign.
你这是以副总统的身份对我说吗
And are you speaking to me as vice president?
我以一个人的身份对你说
I'm speaking to you as a person.
就说是
Blame it on...
弗兰西斯的死带来的压力  总统职务的重荷
the strain after Francis' death, the strain of the office itself.
说辞总是有  但你现在最好的结果
Language can be found, but the best you can hope for now...
就是带着尊严离开
is a dignified exit.
他最令人动容之处  在于他没法不如此
What's so moving about him is he can't help himself.
如此言行得体  充满人性
He can't help being decent. Human.
他那光荣的缺陷
His glorious flaw.
这意味着
What this means is
他们会行动的
they're gonna go through with it.
不  马克
No, Mark.
我哪也不去
I'm staying right where I am.
给你两分钟
You got two minutes.
圣达菲警局
这不是瑞秋·波斯纳
That's not Rachel Posner.
是吗
Is it?
你认识瑞秋·波斯纳
You knew Rachel Posner.
应该
I mean...
算是吧
yeah, I guess.
你和她熟到可以把她名字给别人
Enough to use her name for someone else's ID?
这就是你做的生意吧
That's what you do, isn't it?
给下位客户前一个人的名字
Kind of pay the names forward?
不是
No.
你给了瑞秋什么假名
What name did you give Rachel?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
我说真的
I don't.
你最后一次见到她是什么时候
When did you last see her?
饶了我吧
Come on.
可能几年前吧
Couple of years ago or something.
在她上班的地方
It was where she worked.
她死了吗
Is she dead?
-跟我没关系  -你是不是帮凶
- I got nothing to do with that. - Did you help kill her?
我在跟你说话
I'm talking to you.
别这样  我要找律师
Man. I want my lawyer.
你认识
Do you know...
道格·斯坦普吗
Doug Stamper?
不认识
No.
你给了她什么假名
What name did you give her?
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
丽莎
Lisa.
-丽莎  -嗯  丽莎  凯茜
- Lisa? - Yeah. Lisa Cassie.
-丽莎·凯茜  -凯茜  丽莎
- Lisa Cassie? - Cassie, Lisa.
-对  -丽莎和凯茜
- Yeah. - Lisa and Cassie?
你回到白宫了
Back at the White House.
你住进了他的房间
You took his room.
更宽敞些
It's bigger.
你能告诉我为什么
Can you tell me why
我们非要现在在这里见面吗
it was so important that we meet here and now?
老实说  我是希望能在白宫西楼会面的
Honestly, I was hoping we could meet in the West Wing.
我已经在这里足不出户...
I haven't left the residence in...
我相信你还是看新闻的
Well, I'm sure you still read the news.
而且你的赦免
And your pardon...
没有帮到我或弗兰西斯
hasn't helped me or Francis.
我在这里感觉不舒服
I don't feel comfortable here.
不管你在这里有什么不好的回忆  道格
Whatever bad memories you may have, Doug...
有时候要花很长时间才能理解
sometimes it takes a long time to understand
是谁真正伤害了我们
who's the real source of our harm.
我没能让你相信我
And I have failed to make you trust me,
这太遗憾了
and that's a shame.
我相信我所了解的
I trust what I know.
你有很多敌人  他们低估了你
You have enemies, and they underestimate you.
你认为他们会怎样攻击我
And how do you think they'll come at me?
科尔议员对你说什么了吗
Has Congressman Cole said anything to you?
我觉得她还活着
I think she's alive.
凯茜·杜兰特
Cathy Durant.
我不知道她在哪里或在搞什么事  但是...
I don't know where she is or what she's up to, but...
我知道你会想知道的
I knew you'd want to know.
我想让你知道一件事情
I want you to know something.
弗兰西斯死在这间屋子里
Francis died in this room.
我告诉大家他死在我床上
I told everyone it was in my bed.
但其实就在这片地板上
But it was right there on the floor.
不管是谁杀了他
Whoever killed him.
我遗漏了什么吗
Am I missing something?
杀了他的人
Whoever killed him
将得到她或他应有的下场
will get what she or he deserves.
时机决定了宇宙的形状
Timing decided the shape of the universe.
谁说的
Who said that?
我
Me.
地狱是明白得太晚的真理
Hell is truth seen too late.
这是你说的吗
Did you say that?
托马斯·霍布斯
Thomas Hobbes.
厄舍
Usher...
你下注
your bet.
-我要看牌  谢谢  -别这么礼貌
- I'll check, please. - Don't be polite.
我以前和你玩过
I played with you before.
我知道你有好牌
I know you're holding.
比尔  你确定吗
Bill, you sure?
我可以在下一手分牌给你
I can deal you in on the next hand.
-我不玩  -她真疯了吗
- I don't play. - Is it true she's a basket case?
或者就是一个普通的民主党人
Or just a plain old Democrat.
我会把信准备好
So, I'll have the letter.
要看我的牌得再加一百
That's a hundred to see mine.
等时间到了  汉克
And when it comes time, Hank,
我不想最后
I don't want to end up
在参议院里  一手拿着一张纸
on the Senate floor with a piece of paper in one hand--
另一只手上只有你的蛋
And your balls in the other?
我们都是过来人
We've all been there.
别说我的蛋了
Just keep my balls out of it.
厄舍  你要让我去拉票
Usher, you want me to whip,
却不让我告诉参议员们他们在为什么投票
but you don't want me to tell my senators what they're voting on.
还要不经过讨论就通过
And pass without debate.
我不跟
I'm out.
至少告诉我他们会得到什么
At least tell me what they're getting.
白宫的新主人
A new resident in the White House.
总统先生
Well, Mr. President.
你是跟还是不跟
Are you in or are you out?
我跟
I call.
还有...
And...
加注500
bump you 500.
我永远不会称这里为敌方领地
I would never call this enemy territory.
听起来可能有点奇怪
It might sound quaint,
但我相信共和制
but I believe in the Republic.
感谢你的到来
Well, thank you for coming.
这种媒体的攻击
It's not sustainable.
是持续不下去的
This media onslaught.
不知你是否可以考虑叫你的狗收手
I wonder if you'd consider calling off the dogs.
就暂缓一下  几天就行
All I'm asking for is a pause. Couple of days or so.
你恭维我了  总统女士
You flatter me, Madam President.
但我的能力也不过如此
But my reach only goes so far.
看来他们想让你辞职
It seems they want you to resign.
是谁想
Who's they?
谁不想
Who isn't?
请原谅我的直言不讳
Pardon my bluntness.
不  我喜欢直言不讳  这样节省时间
Oh, no, I enjoy bluntness. Saves time.
但我是否应该因身为女性而辞职
But should I resign for the high crime of being a female?
我认为有比那更深刻的原因
Oh, I think the reasoning goes deeper than that.
我认为...
I think...
这只是我个人的观点
and this is just my perspective,
-如果你想听的话  -请尽管说
- if you want to hear it. - Oh, please.
我们家族与你之间的争斗
Dueling agendas between my family,
已经开始自行发展了
and, well, you, have taken on their own life.
从某种意义上说  你丈夫又不肯放过你
And in some sense, your husband just won't leave you alone,
是吧
will he?
我无法改变过去
I can't change history.
不过有时候你肯定希望自己能
I'll bet sometimes you'd like to.
你不想抹掉他吗
Wouldn't you like to erase him?
总统女士
Madam President...
你已故的丈夫跟我妈妈说了许多事
your dead husband told my mother things.
你不想让全世界知道的事
Things you don't want the world to know.
我觉得  一个死人的话没什么用
A dead man's words are worthless as far as I'm concerned.
要是他所说的能被证实就不一样了
Not when his claims can be verified.
不过有办法让关于某个人的记忆消失
It's possible to make the memory of a person disappear.
用数字手段
Digitally.
至少能把记忆移得远远的
Move them far into the background, anyways.
总是有方法的
There are ways.
算法
Algorithms.
你是个非常自信的年轻人
You're a very confident young man.
你的作为也能消失
Even your deeds can go away.
我能让我们更容易通力合作
Now, I can make it easier for all of us to work together.
你妈妈知道你来了吗
Does your mother know you're here?
不知道
No.
就是好奇一问  你最早的记忆是什么
Just out of curiosity, what's your first memory?
关于她的最早的记忆
Your first memory of her?
这个问题好奇怪
That's a strange question.
我就是好奇
I was just curious.
我有一张她接住我的照片
I have a photograph of her catching me.
我妈妈把我扔到空中
My mother had thrown me up into the air,
我舅舅用他的新尼康相机抓拍到了那一幕
and my uncle snapped a picture on his new Nikon camera.
她喜气洋洋
She's beaming.
特别高兴
Gleeful.
我一直珍藏着那张照片
I treasure that photo.
我记忆中的她就是这样的
It's how I like to think of her.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
问问安奈特
Ask Annette--
问问你妈妈  你是从哪来的
Ask your mother where you came from.
天怎么还没黑
It's still light out?
你真是让人大汗淋漓
You're very dehydrating.
我知道
I know, I know.
你想谈谈协议
You want to talk about the deal.
你把我排除在外  简
You excluded me, Jane.
等尘埃落定  我会满足你的
When the dust settles, I'll give you what you want.
我没怀疑过你的本事
Never doubted your value.
你见到我的手机了吗
Have you seen my phone?
在卫生间
It's in the restroom.
该死
Shit.
你是不是动了我的...
Did you do something to my--
我去环保署了
I went to the EPA.
什么都没有
There is nothing.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
有些人  混进了城里
There are people walking around this town,
穿着普通  装成是本地人
dressed down, acting like they belong.
但我知道他们不是
But I know they don't.
你被威胁了吗
Have you been threatened?
拜托  他们不会蠢到威胁我的
Come on, they're too smart for that.
所以他们在跟踪你
Well, so they're following you.
但如果什么都没有
But if there's nothing,
-那就...  -我有截图
- then there's-- - I have screenshots...
邮件往来的截图
of the e-mail chain.
因为他们做了错事
'Cause it's wrong what they did.
因为我太傻了
'Cause I'm so stupid.
傻到相信在这个操蛋的世界里
So stupid to believe in doing the right thing
坚持正义
in this totally fucked up world.
其中有一封邮件是比尔·谢泼德的办公室发的
There's an e-mail from Bill Shepherd's office in the chain.
我说过  他们早就知道
I told you. They knew.
他们早就知道会出人命
They knew somebody was gonna die.
我得走了
I gotta go.
等等
Wait.
怎么了
What?
你的手机
Your phone.
-手机怎么了  -我信不过
- What about it? - I don't trust it.
我丢掉了我的手机
I got rid of mine.
我发誓  感觉像是他们在跟踪我的手机
I swear, it felt like they were following my phone
而不是我
and not me.
-怎么会  -我得走了
- How? - Look, I gotta go.
我会再联系你的
I'll reach out to you.
-好吗  -不  你说什么...
- Okay? - No. What--
谢泼德自由基金会
民主在运作
她在沙特阿拉伯的某个地方
She's somewhere in Saudi Arabia.
女士  她落入敌人手中  对我们风险极大
Ma'am, she poses a significant risk in enemy hands.
你知道的
You know that.
美国不与恐怖分子谈判
The United States does not negotiate with terrorists.
不用谈判  特战司令部在制定几种行动计划
No negotiations. Options are being drawn up at SOCOM.
但必须有行政命令才能执行
But nothing can happen without an executive order.
那...
Well, then.
等你当了总统  再发布行政命令好了
That's gonna have to happen when you're president.
简被捕  谁的秘密都不安全
No one's secrets are safe with Jane in captivity.
你可能会比我更担心这一点
That may be more concerning for you than it is for me.
捅了马蜂窝  该开始推进计划了
Kicking the hornet's nest. Time to move this thing along.
-你个自大的混蛋  -冷静
- You arrogant little prick. - Please, just calm down.
你以为我发现不了吗
Did you think I wouldn't find out?
你骂人的话  我可要走了
I'm not staying if there's name-calling.
我怎么骂都不过分  安妮
There's not enough names to call him, Annie.
真是蠢得清奇
Such stunning stupidity.
头韵押得真妙  比尔舅舅
Nice alliteration, Uncle Bill.
这条毛巾都比你聪明
This towel is smarter than you.
这扇窗都比你聪明
This window is smarter than you.
这块地毯都比你聪明
This rug is smarter than you.
-你好  赛斯  -你好  先生
- Hello, Seth. - Hello, sir.
赛斯都比你聪明
Seth is smarter than you!
我眉毛上的汗
The sweat on my brow
-都比你聪明  邓肯  -我的天啊
- is smarter than you, Duncan. - Jesus H. Christ,
-行了吧  -因为我眉毛上的汗
- spare us. - Because sweat on my brow,
至少都清楚不能擅自去见
would have at least known not to pay an unsanctioned visit
-美国总统  -放开他
- to the President of the United States. - Get your hands off him.
我知道你不舒服  但
I know you're not feeling well, but...
这话是什么意思
Well, what the hell is that supposed to mean, anyway?
你不能这样
You can't act like this.
我只是想帮忙  是她请我去的
You know, I was trying to help. She invited me and--
那你就去了  真他妈白痴
And you went, like a fucking idiot--
我想成为沟通桥梁
I wanted to be a bridge.
闭嘴  你们俩都闭嘴吧
Shut up, both of you, just shut up.
天啊  我们有什么没为你做到的吗
God, is there anything we haven't done for you?
家人之间就该如此
Well, you know, that's what people do for family.
-为彼此不惜一切  -听着  你不该去的
- Anything. - Listen, you shouldn't have gone.
她不值得信任  我跟你说过无数次了
She can't be trusted, as I've told you a million times.
他坏了我们的时机
He jeopardized our timing.
他坏了我们对她下手的时机
He jeopardized our timing with her!
我再也受不了男人吵架了
I can't stand the sound of male arguing anymore.
她让我问你件事
You know, she told me to ask you something.
她让我问你我从哪来的
She told me to ask you where I came from.
赛斯  赛斯
Seth. Seth!
16周
Sixteen weeks.
她跟丈夫怀的那个孩子
The one from the pregnancy with her husband.
安妮  这的确不是好主意
Annie, I do think it'd be a mistake.
赛斯  确认下
Seth, confirm it.
-没错  16周  -她丈夫告诉我的
- That's right. Sixteen weeks. - Her husband told me.
但你不知道事态会怎样发展  是吧
But you don't know how it's gonna play. Okay?
可能事与愿违  让人们同情她
It could backfire. Get her sympathy.
-谁会等到16周  -我们无法控制舆论发展
- Who waits 16 weeks? - The narrative can't be controlled--
什么人会这么做  人们会谈论这个
What kind of person, that's what people will be talking about.
给马克打电话  立刻开始
Let's get Mark on the phone. We start this now.
我们就叫她丽萨
Only "Lisa" is what we called her.
她在中心市场的同事
The lady at Central Market, where she worked,
说你好几次去找过她
said you stopped by a few times asking for her.
她欠我们钱  但
She owed us some money, but...
她死了吗
She dead?
不知道
I don't know.
里面没多少东西
There's not much in there.
几封信
Some letters.
纸片  清单  还有
Scraps and lists and...
照片
Picture.
都不值钱
Nothing, really.
我们国家遇到了问题
Our country has a problem right now.
总统
The president,
她无视高级顾问的建议
she has ignored the advice of her senior advisers,
那都是有学问  有作战经验的人
people who have studied and fought battles.
她的精神状态让我们陷入更糟的...
Her state of mind has left us in a weakened...
国防部长称总统无视高级顾问
我们得守住阵线
We need to hold the line
直到国家回到正轨
till our country gets back on course.
这段视频令人震惊
That is a truly stunning video.
对于国防部长对总统的批评
What is your reaction to the secretary of defense's critique
你怎么看
of this president?
国防部长汉纳是四星海军陆战队将军
Secretary Defense Hanna is a four-star Marine General
服役四十多年了
with over 40 years of service to this country.
我理解他的失望
I understand his frustration.
据称马克·厄舍掌握着白宫实权
Is there any truth to the idea that Mark Usher
就像小布什的迪克·切尼  是真的吗
is the Dick Cheney of this White House?
不  迪克·切尼只有一个
No, there is only one Dick Cheney.
-这话不假  -马克·厄舍
- Okay, fair enough. - Mark Usher is
就是这届政府的马克·厄舍
the Mark Usher of this White House.
那你怎么定位现任副总统的角色
So, how would you characterize the vice president's role?
副总统受到了内阁的全力支持
The vice president has the full support of the entire cabinet.
那总统呢
And the president?
总统能为自己说话
Well, the president speaks for herself.
你的意思是国防部长
Are you suggesting that the Secretary of Defense
不是唯一不满总统的人吗
is not the only one who's frustrated with this president?
劳伦斯  这座城市充斥着流言蜚语
You know, Lawrence, this town feeds off of rumor and gossip
-这只会适得其反  -吃点吗
- and it's counter-productive. - Raha?
这是分散注意力  我不来这套
It's a distraction. I don't work that way.
你不来这套  那你来哪套
You don't work that way. How do you work?
-你在现任总统那里来哪套  -你有电话
- How do you work with this president? - You have a call.
是你的总统
It's your president.
这届政府无法正常运转了吗
Is this a dysfunctional administration?
我与总统的关系
My relationship with this...
克莱尔
Claire.
简  我只想知道
Jane, I just need to know
他们到底什么时候动手
exactly when they're going to pull the trigger.
你不想回家吗
Don't you want to come home?
你倒是挺开心的样子
You look like you're having fun.
我认为你们是有真情的
I see real affection there.
当然外界也有关于我和汤姆的谣言
And, listen, there were rumors about Tom and me, of course,
但全都不是真的
but nothing to them.
他对我来说像个弟弟
He was like a brother to me.
总能安慰我
So comforting.
也正是因此  这才更让人难过
Which is what makes this all the more difficult.
真相是  凯尔茜
The truth is, Kelsey...
是俄罗斯人杀了汤姆
the Russians killed Tom...
马克·厄舍帮忙掩盖了事实
and Mark Usher covered it up.
我将竭尽所能让他为此事负责
Now, I'm doing my best to hold him accountable,
但我需要你的帮助
but I need your help.
我要你告诉联调局
I need you to tell the FBI
你和汤姆的关系
about your relationship with Tom.
-总统女士  我...  -我懂  没关系的
- Madam President, I-- - I know. It's fine.
说你俩当时在约会
You just say you were dating.
在谈恋爱
You were in love.
有次在私下里
And in a private moment,
他向你透露了他怀疑
he told you about his suspicions regarding
马克·厄舍与俄罗斯串谋
Mark Usher and his collusion with Russia.
而你最后一次见到他时
And the last time you saw him,
他正要去副总统的宅邸
he was on his way to the vice president's home
与他对峙
to confront him.
我不会让副总统逍遥法外的
I'm not going to let the vice president get away with this.
你和我身为女人
You and I, as women,
我们必须反击
we have to fight back.
我需要你和我并肩作战
I need you by my side.
在我们送出信之前
And before we transmit the letter,
我想请所有人低下头
I'd like to suggest we all take a moment to bow our heads
为我们伟大的祖国祈祷
and pray for this great nation.
能把信递给我吗
Could you pass me that letter?
还有  把你们的东西收好
And gather all of your things.
在场所有内阁成员
Every single cabinet member in this room
都可以走了
is dismissed.
你们都被解雇了
You're all fired.
送他们出去
Escort them out.
你知道
You know,
我从没想过你是
I never took you for someone
想入主白宫的人
who wanted to get himself into the Oval.
不过是个四年的饭碗  幸运的话是八年
All it is, is a four year job, eight if you're lucky.
你在哪
Where are you?
什么
What?
好  我马上回来
All right. I'm on my way back.
要是她干预签署  那就是妨碍司法
Listen, if she prevented the signing, that's obstruction.
可能会使她遭弹劾
And likely, it's impeachable.
听见了吗
You hear me?
细节仍在传来
Details are still coming in.
但是据了解  今天联调局
But we're being told there are reports that the FBI...
-马克  -收到证据显示
- Mark. - ...has today been provided evidence...
-去看电视  -马克·厄舍与俄国官员
- Get to a television. - ...that Mark Usher had quote...
-或是电脑  -有"情节重大
- Or a computer. - ..."significant and ongoing...
联调局调查副总统与俄罗斯勾结的指控
或是打开电台
Or a goddamn radio.
且仍在持续的私下联系"
...contact outside the logs with Russian officials."
这促成了总统近期所签署的
This leading up to and during the president's
反应两极化的叙利亚和平协议
recent polarizing Syrian peace deal.
联调局会调查此事
The FBI's expected to look into the matter,
但他们尚未宣布是否会启动
but has yet to announce whether or not they are opening
正式调查
an official investigation.
如果属实  这将是本届多灾多难的政府
If so, this could be a catastrophic setback
遭遇的又一灾难性挫败
for an already-beleaguered administration.
在我们开始之前  我想给你一个请辞的机会
Before we begin, I'd like to offer you the chance to resign.
那我就不打扰你了
I'll leave you to it then.
我和俄罗斯从没有过非正式联系  从来没有
I never had any contact with any Russians outside the logs. None.
1991年夏天你曾在副外交部长左尔金位于
You vacationed at Deputy Foreign Minister Zorkin's family dacha
-黑海的乡间别墅度假  -二十年前的事了
- on the Black Sea in summer 1991. - That was 20 years ago.
我们回溯一下  从凯尔茜·斯图尔特小姐的证词
Let's work backwards, start with questions that have arisen
引起的疑问开始
after Ms. Kelsey Stewart's deposition.
谁
Who?
我们定位她的手机在贝尔波特的一家酒水店
We located her phone in a liquor store in Bellport.
她知道应用的事了
She knows about the app.
应该是吧
We should assume so.
你告诉我舅舅了吗
Have you told my uncle yet?
我联系不上他
I can't reach him.
我也联系不上你母亲
I can't reach your mother, either.
我们已经派人追踪那位记者
We have some men tracking the journalist.
我们还不知道她是否取得了任何证据
But we don't even know if she has her hands on anything yet.
-谢泼德先生的包裹  -谢谢
- Package for Mr. Shepherd. - Oh, thank you.
写着是给你的
This is addressed to you.
请让我独处一会儿
Leave me alone, please.
我是凯瑟琳·杜兰特
My name is Catherine Durant.
今天是2017年7月18日  星期二
Today is Tuesday, July 18, 2017.
时间是
And the time...
晚上8点37分
8:37 p.m.
在我开始之前  我想说
Now, before I begin, let me just say...
历史必将带给
that every punishment
克莱尔·安德伍德的所有惩罚
that history will surely visit upon Claire Underwood
都是她罪有应得
will be exactly what she deserves.
我万分懊悔当初接受了她丈夫提供的
I rue the day that I accepted her husband's offer
国务卿一职
of secretary of state.
好了
Now, then...
我发誓我接下来绝无虚言
I hereby swear that everything I'm about to say is the truth.
她丈夫六小时前失踪了
Her husband has disappeared, as of six hours ago.
-你还想听吗  -不了
- Do you want to hear any more? - No.
我知道后面是什么
I know the rest.
你觉得是俄罗斯人帮他们逃掉的吗
Do you think the Russians got them out?
不  我能肯定是
Uh, no, I'm sure of it.
你觉得她发给其他人了吗
Do you think she sent it to anyone else?
发了我们早就知道了
We would know about it by now.
我让纳森候命于你
I've asked Nathan to be available to you.
我知道你俩合作很默契
I know how well you two work with one another.
我们会找到她的
We'll find her.
道格  我还没忘
And, Doug, I haven't forgotten
我们对彼此的承诺
about the promise we made to each other.
但愿你也没有
I hope you haven't.
我刚从新墨西哥州回来
I just got back from New Mexico.
你把瑞秋怎么了  还是把凯茜怎么了
What did you do with Rachel? Or is it Cassie?
我离你只有五分钟路程
I'm five minutes away.
挂了电话
Hang up the phone.
-道格  -挂掉
- Doug-- - Hang it up
不然我再不会联系你
or you'll never hear from me again.
我去找你
I'll come to you.
纳森
Nathan,
你还在听吗
are you still listening?
你相信她会保护你就太傻了
You're a fool to think she'll protect you.
这似乎挺合适  我回来工作后
Seems fitting, somehow, that you're the first
第一个见的人就是你
person I meet with after I've returned to work.
真是好轮回啊
There's something very full circle about it.
你跟你儿子谈过咯
So, you've talked to your son.
准确说那不是你儿子
Or rather, not your son.
你知道那时候胎儿有多大了吗
Do you know how developed a fetus is by then?
16周
Sixteen weeks is...
那可是成型的胎儿
beyond the beyond.
16周的胎儿有这么大了
That is what 16 weeks looks like.
这画面在我脑海中挥之不去
That is what I can't get out of my head.
我在学梅乐蒂·科鲁兹说话呢
I'm quoting Melody Cruz here, by the way.
她刚录好视频  明天就放
She just taped her segment, due to run tomorrow.
还有道具增强表现力
Visual aids and everything.
美国人民会首次听到
For the first time ever, Americans will hear the story
膝下无子的总统
of a childless president...
在婚后
who had an abortion,
做了流产
while married,
打掉了16周的胎儿
at 16 weeks.
我就想看看你的表情
I wanted to see your face.
我想看你意识到弗兰克的背叛
I wanted to see Frank's betrayal register.
现在谁都管不住自己的嘴
Nobody can keep their mouths shut these days.
秘密都带进坟墓了还能被挖出来
Not even to-the-death secrets are safe.
真可耻
It's shameful.
但说实话  哪样更痛苦
But honestly, what's worse?
他泄露了你的秘密
That he betrayed your secret
还是你等到16周才堕胎
or that you waited until 16 weeks?
你和你的党派
You and your party.
就一副道貌岸然的样子
Your moral rectitude, how convenient.
你自己的话你一个字也不信  安奈特
You don't even believe half of what you say, Annette.
放吧
Run it.
科鲁兹的报道
Cruz's piece.
放吧
Run it.
然后回去
And then go home
跟邓肯说说他怎么来的
and talk to Duncan about the beginning of life.
你走之前
But actually before you go,
我想给你看样东西  来
I want to show you something. Come with me.
见过我的新内阁
Meet my new cabinet.
我就想看看你的表情
I just wanted to see your face.
谢谢大家临危受命
Thank you all for assembling at such short notice.
我想感谢各位的奉献精神
And I want to thank you for your willingness to serve.
我很期待能共同建立一个新美国
I am looking forward to building a new America together
我们就从今天开始
and our work begins today.
现在  请你们
Now, if you could all
将左手放在自己面前的《宪法》上
place your left hand on the Constitution in front of you.
跟我念
And repeat after me:
本人庄严宣誓
I do solemnly swear
下手绝不留情
to take no prisoners.
今年6月第一夫人梅兰妮因肾病紧急入院做了手术
根据病情判断  媒体以为术后三五天她就会重回公众视野
但是没想到梅兰妮一直玩失踪  长达25天没在媒体前露面
第一夫人玩失踪引发媒体各种猜测  有的说她乘机整容
有的说她跟老公特朗普闹翻离宫出走...
不过25天后  她再次出现在公共场合  所有谣言都不攻自破
不过白宫也一直没有解释为什么第一夫人需要这么长时间闭门养病
宪法第25修正案主要规定当总统和副总统职位出现空缺时
应怎样启动继任程序  历史上因总统副总统辞职
总统体检麻醉等原因  共启用过六次
本集中由副总统和内阁启动继任程序的第四条款  历史上从未被使用过
特朗普上任后  他的政敌和媒体
一直对他的施政能力和各种言论进行猛烈攻击
一些人曾在电视访谈中称特朗普性情乖张  像疯了一样
精神状态不适合履行总统职务  应该启动第25修正案
18年9月21日  《纽约时报》爆料称  司法部副部长罗森斯坦
曾私下建议启用第25修正案  把特朗普从总统位置上赶下来
并表示自己可以暗中配戴窃听装置进入总统办公室
偷录特朗普讲话  以证明总统无法控制白宫局势
罗森斯坦本人坚决否认《纽约时报》的报道
但据说特朗普看了报道后一度想要炒掉罗森斯坦  但是后来回转心意
在空军一号上同罗森斯坦面对面交谈后  决定不去动他
罗森斯坦是负责通俄门调查的最高级官员
如果特朗普把他炒掉  可能会引发"总统干预司法"的危机